Sampath Mestha

Frontend Developer

Personal Details

+91- 8497818677
sampathmestha@gmail.com
LinkedIn | Github

Professional Summary

Skilled Frontend Developer with 2 years of experience in creating responsive user applications and websites. Proficient in using React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to develop effective user interfaces according to client requirements. Experience in designing web applications with different tools related to the React platform.

Employment History

Front end Developer at Searchblox software, inc

Sep 2022 - PRESENT

Languages: React, JavaScript, Vite and OpenAl.

- Working with the SearchBlox search platform for UI templates/updates.
- Creating/Updating React Search UI templates for customers.
- Created many responsive and reusable components for future use and monitoring & maintaining front-end performance.
- Troubleshooting & debugging to boost the overall performance.

Front end Developer at SocioClub - Intern

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

Languages: React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

- Worked on creating responsive web pages to cater to multiple media devices. and Built reusable components with React.
- Worked on images for alignment within the application.

Major Skills

React

JavaScript

Next.js

HTML5

CSS3

Redux

Tailwind CSS

Skills Familiar with

TypeScript

NodeJS

Database

MongoDB

MySQL

Firebase

Udemy - <u>Certificates</u>

Micro-Frontend
UI Accessibility

Projects

Next.js Events App

Github | Live

Languages: Next.js, React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

I have created an events app using Next.js. This has covered all the latest next.js features. This App is Responsive for all types of devices. Optimized this app using the optimization feature which is provided by the next.js.

React Contact Management App And Corona cases Map and Chart

Github | Live

Languages: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Redux, React-charts-2, HTML and Tailwind CSS.

I have created a Contact Management App where we can Add, Delete and Edit the Data of Contacts and also included a Chart and Map which visualizes Corona Cases of the world. This App is Responsive for all types of devices.

Education

St. Aloysius College (Autonomous), Mangalore — *BCA* Bachelor of Computer Applications

Jun 2019 - Jun 2022 CGPA - 8/10

Declaration:

I hereby declare that above mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above mentioned particulars.

Languages

English

Hindi

Kannada